A Finding Aid to the Ben Benn Papers, 1905-1993, in the Archives of American Art AAA.bennben
Archives of American Art
- Diaries, Notebooks, and Scrapbooks, 1915-1977, undated; Series 3; 11 Folders Boxes 4-5
  - Diaries, 1943-1959 (Box 4, Folder 18-20)
  - Diaries, 1960-1977 (Box 5, Folder 1-4)
  - Notebook and Notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook #1, 1915-1960, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook #2, 1949-1967, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook #3, 1916-1972, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Personal Business Records, circa 1910-1979, undated; Series 4; 9 Folders Box 5
  Scattered personal business records that include miscellaneous receipts, a check register, a bank statement, an eviction notice, a file pertaining to the conservatorship of Ben Benn's estate, address books and lists, and lists and records of paintings purchased or held on consignment.
  - Paintings Sold or Held by Galleries, circa 1910- circa 1971, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Receipts, 1919-1968 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Eviction Notice, Benn's residence at 206 West 105th Street, NY, NY, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Check Register, 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Bank Statement, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Address Books and Lists, 1965-1966, undated (Box 5, Folder 14-16)
  - Legal Proceeding Pertaining to Conservatorship of Ben Benn, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Artwork, 1924-1974, undated; Series 5; 6 Folders Box 5, 7; 6 oversized items
  Sketches and sketchbooks by Ben Benn, mostly in pencil, and fashion sketches, in pencil, by Velida Benn. Also found is an etching inscribed to Ben Benn from Marie G. Williams, 1924.
  - Etching, 1924 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Sketches, 1937-1974, undated (Box 5, Folder 19-24)
  - Oversized Sketchbooks, 1957-1972, undated (Box 7, Folder 1-5)
  - Oversized Sketches, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Printed Material, 1911-1991, undated; Series 6; 2 Linear feet Boxes 5-6
  This series houses announcements, exhibition catalogs, newspaper and magazine clippings, news bulletins, programs, reproductions and miscellaneous printed materials. Exhibition catalogs include Ben Benn: Painter, The Jewish Museum, 1965 and Ben Benn, An American Painter, 1884-1983, Hammer Galleries, 1983. Magazine clippings include numerous reviews of Benn's work by Sidney Geist, Hilton Kramer, and Sidney Tillim. Also found are miscellaneous literary and art-related periodicals featuring Benn's artwork and Artists and Writers Chap Books (1933-1935) that include artwork by Velida and Ben Benn.
  - Exhibition Announcements, 1911-1977, undated (Box 5, Folder 25-34)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1918-1944 (Box 5, Folder 35-37)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1950-1991 (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1915-1982, undated (Box 6, Folder 4-9)
  - Magazine clippings, 1916-1965, undated (Box 6, Folder 10-14)
  - Artists and Writers Chapbook, 1933-1935 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - News Bulletins, 1936-1937, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Programs, 1919-1950, undated (Box 6, Folder 17-18)
  - Offprints, various, 1927-1940, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Miscellaneous printed material, 1914-1975, undated (Box 6, Folder 20-24)
  - Reproductions, 1905-1975, undated (Box 6, Folder 25-27)
  - Books, circa 1919, undated (Box 6, Folder 28-30)
- Photographs and Negatives, 1920-1969, undated; Series 7; 6 Folders Box 6
  Photographs of works of art, personal photographs, and negatives that include images of Benn's paintings and exhibition installation shots; photographs and snapshots of Ben and Velida Benn, including an image of Benn taken by Peter A. Juley and Son; and negatives of Ben Benn and works of art.
  - Photographs of Works of Art, 1920-1964, undated (Box 6, Folder 31-32)
  - Photographs of Ben and Velida Benn, 1936, 1963-1969, undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Photographs of Exhibition Installations, undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Photographs of Family Members, undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Negatives, undated (Box 6, Folder 36)